"超感神探" 前情提要...
Previously on "the mentalist"...
Van Pelt在Bertram的办公室发现了加密文件
Van Pelt found some coded files in Bertram's office.
像个名单
It looks like a list.
- 我叫Patrick - 我叫Kim
- Patrick.  - Kim.
- 谢谢你 我需要陪伴  - 谁不需要陪伴呢?
- Thank you for this. I needed the company.  - Who doesn't?
我是来和你谈条件的
I'm here to make you an offer.
如果你愿意来为我们工作 联邦调查局很愿意...
The Bureau is willing to drop all the charges against you...
- 撤销对你的一切指控  - 为联邦调查局工作?
- if you come and work for us.  - For the FBI?
我的条款 我要你读完之后
My terms. I need you to read them
签上名
and sign it.
这些我们可以达成
We can work with this.
我把我家里电话留给你...
I'm gonna give you my home phone number...
说不定哪天你就回国了
in case you ever make it back to the States.
你现在脚踏美国的领土 我代表联邦政府
You are on U.S.soil now, I am the Federal Government,
告诉你 这...
and I am telling you that this...
才是协议
is the deal.
那不过是张餐巾 要么签 要么走
That is a napkin. Take it or leave it.
我走
I'll leave it.
- Kim 是你?  - 是Fischer探员
- Kim?  - Agent Fischer.
Fischer探员
Agent fischer.
华盛顿 Cannon River警局
订书机去哪了?
Have you seen the stapler?
昨天坏了
It busted yesterday.
- 我们只有一个吗?  - 呃...
- We have another one?  - Um...
你可以用复印机
You know, maybe try the copying machine.
- 复印机也可以订的  - 那样会浪费纸吧?
- It has a staple function.  - Isn't that a waste of paper?
不会 我们就纸最多
No, we have tons of paper.
我还是去找个回形针吧
I'm gonna go with a paper clip.
Fischer探员
Agent Fischer.
Lisbon警长 我们能聊几句吗?
Chief Lisbon. Can we talk?
这好可爱啊
It's adorable.
请坐
Please. Sit down.
Jane还好吗?
How's Jane?
他还在拘留
He is still in detention.
我知道
I know.
他们不送我的信
They won't deliver my letters.
都三个月了
Three months now.
他被蓄意隔离了
He's being kept in isolation by design.
蓄意?
By design?
你是说 除非他答应你们的要求
You mean until he does what you want.
- 我们想帮助他  - 你想利用他
- We want to help him out.  - You want to use him.
那样不好吗?
Is that so bad?
你没有注意到吧
In case you haven't noticed,
Jane就不是当联邦探员的料
Jane is hardly Federal Agent material.
那他是加州探员的料?
Was he State Agent material?
都不是 但至少他想在那儿工作
No, not really, but he wanted to be there.
他在加州调查局的时候 破了悬案十年的
And while he was there, he stopped the 10-year reign
连环杀手案
of a mass murderer
并曝光了警界的腐败组织
and exposed a society of corruption in law enforcement.
这事传遍了大江南北
That spread halfway across the country.
是啊 那些事情都出乎大家的意料 是吧?
Yeah, that didn't exactly go down by the books, did it?
没错 我们知道Jane的工作方式 也知道有风险
Yeah, we know how Jane works. And we know he's a risk.
但他也有好的一面
But we can't ignore the upside.
他结了你接手的每个案子
He closed every case you were ever assigned.
没错 但他有帮手
Yeah, he had help.
所以我今天到这来了
Which is why I'm here.
你想要什么?
What do you want from me?
帮助我 Lisbon
Help me, Lisbon.
国家安全出问题了
There are National Security issues at play.
Jane不和我们合作 除非我们满足他的要求
Jane won't work with us unless we meet his demands.
他太骄傲了 得挫挫锐气
He has too much pride to back down.
你得让他赢 满足他的某项条件
You got to give him a win. Meet one of his demands.
他的某项条件就是你
One of his demands is you.
那就换一个吧
Meet another one.
我们没时间了
We're running out of time.
你就这么忙 以至于你都不能
Is your work here so pressing that you can't take a break
帮帮自己的国家吗?
to help your country?
警长 我用无线电通知了Phelps警员
Hey, Chief, uh, I radioed Officer Phelps.
他会去凯马特(美国零售公司)买一个新的订书机
He can run to Kmart for a new stapler.
要斯温格来恩的还是史丹利牌的?
Swingline or Stanley Bostitch?
德州 奥斯汀市 联邦调查局拘留所
稀客 太好了
Visitor. Splendid.
看你这样子好像不情愿来啊
Not a willing one, based on the posture.
这样就好多了
That's a little better.
很高兴见到你
It's good to see you.
感觉怎么样?
How you holding up?
啊...
Ah...
你懂被监禁的感觉的
You know what incarceration's like.
不太懂
Not really.
没必要装 Lisbon
Well, there's no need to pretend, Lisbon.
我们处境相同
We're both in the same predicament.
怎么会呢? 我自己有家 还有受人尊重的职业
How is that? I have a home and a respected career.
而你却因为谋杀被监禁了
You're locked up for murder.
你在吹毛求疵 我们都被困住了
Eh, you're splitting hairs. We're both trapped.
我怎么就被困住了呢?
How am I trapped?
因为你住在华盛顿
You live in Washington.
我挺喜欢华盛顿的
I love Washington.
说谎
High voice.
你为什么这么顽固?
Why are you being so stubborn?
联邦调查局已经答应你"不用蹲监狱"了
The FBI is offering you a "get out of jail free" card.
- 听你说好像是件好事  - 不是好事吗?
- Well, you make that sound like a good thing.  - Isn't it?
按照他们的条款 就不是
Not on their terms.
如果他们不答应我的条件
If I can't live on my terms,
我最终还是会蹲监狱
I'm in prison anyway.
待在这个拘留小套间也挺舒适的
Might as well just stay in this cozy little detention suite.
行 你自己决定 但今天不行
Well, that's your call, but not today.
联邦调查局逼我来这
The FBI dragged me here,
除非你帮他们破那个案子
and they're not gonna let me go home
他们不会让我回家的
until you help them with a case.
所以快站起来 我们走
So get your ass out of the chair and let's go.
好样的...
Okay...
联邦调查员
Federal officers coming through.
超感神探 第六季第10集
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：有个饭团
时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：笑点滴 波特妹子 初见 捞小盐
校对：爱犀利馒头叔的影子
联邦调查局 奥斯汀分部
这里怎么没有沙发
Hmm. I don't see a couch anywhere.
至少现在别惹麻烦吧
Don't start trouble. At least not yet.
这边
Over here.
我们将会在这个案子上协助纽约警方
We'll be assisting our New York office on this case.
我们的救星到了
And our asset has just arrived.
Jane先生 Lisbon 你们好
Mr. Jane. Lisbon.
你说我是救星 太令我感动了
You called me an asset. That's so touching.
我是一个乐天派
I'm an optimist.
请坐 那我们继续说
We just started briefing, if you'll have a seat.
- 好 嗨 Cho  - 嗨 Jane
- I'm fine. Hey, Cho.  - Hey, Jane.
最近怎么样?
What's going on?
我们正在开会
Hey.  We're in the middle of a briefing.
- 一会聊吧  - 知道了 你好
- We can catch up later.  - Gotcha. Hey there.
这是Abel Schneiderman
This is Abel Schneiderman.
他带领的团队编写了用于
He led the team that wrote the new source code
保护联邦储备银行系统的新源代码
to protect the Federal Reserve Banking System.
两天前 他从他在布鲁克林的公寓里失踪
Two days ago, he disappeared from his loft in Brooklyn.
他的卧室里有争斗的痕迹
There were signs of a struggle in his bedroom.
Schneiderman的手机被摔在地下
Schneiderman's cell phone was busted on the floor.
我们猜测他被绑架了
We are working on the theory that he has been kidnapped.
有人要赎金了吗?
Has there been a ransom demand?
目前还没有 但我们觉得会有
Not yet, but we're expecting it.
他们或者是想要赎金 或者是索要代码
Well, it's either that, or they will break him for the code
去击溃
and launch an attack
美联储电脑系统
on the Federal Reserve Computer System.
Abel所知道的能让我们的银行系统
What Abel knows could bring our banking system
彻底瘫痪
to its knees.
这太有意思了
Oh. This is exciting.
这是我要处理的案子吗?
Is this the case that I'm here for?
我们等你很久了
We're getting to you.
我就知道你看见我了 对吧?
I knew you saw me. Huh?
我就知道
I knew it.
Abel有个年轻的妻子...
Abel has a young wife...
叫Defiance Schneiderman
Defiance Schneiderman.
不难看出 她情绪很激动
Now understandably, she's emotional
而且认定联邦调查局
and believes that the FBI is not utilizing
没有倾其所有去找她丈夫
all of its resources to find her husband.
更糟的是 我们还不能让联邦调查局以外的人知道
And unfortunately, we can't let anyone outside the FBI
Schneiderman先生被绑架了
know that Mr. Schneiderman's been kidnapped.
否则金融系统就会受到重创
Otherwise, it could cripple the financial systems.
纽约当局派了联邦调查局探员
The New York Office sent a FBI Agent
假扮成灵媒
posing as a psychic,
但Schneiderman女士一眼就识破了
but Ms. Schneiderman saw right through that.
当然了 她是吉普赛人
Well, of course. She's a gypsy.
吉普赛女人都多少了解些通灵的事
Woman knows a thing or two about psychics.
那你为什么要说她是吉普赛人?
What makes you say gypsy?
Defiance是个吉普赛人的名字
Well, Defiance is a gypsy name.
你看她的卧室
Look at her bedroom.
那是吉普赛猫薄荷
It's gypsy catnip.
Abel是犹太人 那就说明
Abel there is Jewish, which means
她背弃了自己的宗教结的婚
she turned her back on her entire clan to get married.
而现在她既找不到丈夫 也毫无家庭支援
Now she has a missing husband and no family for support.
所以才会想找灵媒帮忙
It's a psychic 9-1-1.
这就是我们现在了解到的情况
Well... there we are.
开始行动吧
Let's go to work.
奥斯汀国际机场
谢谢
Thank you.
经济舱 我还想着坐联邦喷气式飞机呢
Coach. I was expecting a federal jet,
或者至少也得是直升机吧
or at least a helicopter.
我要坐靠近走道的位置
Call the aisle seat.
你要按照上面说的坐
You'll sit where you're told.
别紧张
You know, you can relax.
没事
Everything's good.
你还是一个联邦囚犯呢
You're still a Federal detainee,
并受我监管 所以我不会掉以轻心的
and you're in my charge, so, no, I won't relax.
照我说的做 明白吗?
And you'll do as I tell you, you understand?
我知道 Kim
Oh, I understand you, Kim.
我很了解你... 比你自己都了解你
I understand you very well... better than you do yourself.
你要待在联邦调查局成员的
You will stay within arm's length
一臂范围之内
of FBI personnel at all times.
只要你轻举妄动 就会被重新送回拘留所
Any foolishness, and you go back to detention.
她在岛上可不是这样
She wasn't at all like this on the island.
- 那她在岛上是什么样?  - 我当时在做卧底
- How was she on the island?  - I was undercover.
你是说你当时在撒谎
You mean you were lying.
我当时在伪装
I was using a false persona.
我可不这样认为
Actually, I don't think so.
我觉得那才是真的你
I think that was the real you.
而这个严厉的联邦调查局探员
I think this Federal she-wolf shtick is,
才是个伪装
in fact, a false persona.
不 这就是真的我
No. This is the real me.
我们该登机了
Hmm. We're boarding.
记住规则
Remember the rules.
纽约 布鲁克林
啊
Ahh.
我喜欢这种肉和洋葱味
I love the smell of reclaimed meat and onion water.
能借我20块吗?
Do you have a $20?
谢了
Thank you.
Liaison和纽约当局已经在楼上候着了
Liaison with the New York office is waiting upstairs.
你们两个待在这看门
You two, stay here and cover the exits.
这里有两个出口... 一个在西边 一个在南边
There are two... west and south.
扣留住想要离开这栋楼的人
Detain anyone who tries to leave the building.
嘿
Hey.
一臂范围 记得吗?
Arm's length, remember?
记得 我只是有点饿
Yeah. I'm just a little hungry.
我不管
I don't care.
- 我都付过钱了  - 走
- I've already paid.  - Now.
这是Schneidermans住的地方
This is where the Schneidermans live.
都像个废弃的仓库了
It's mostly an abandoned storage building,
但顶层还有几家租户
But there are some renters on the top floor.
没有监控像头
No security cameras.
哪种租户?
What kind of renters?
就那种边缘性租户... 像什么艺术家 流浪汉
Usual fringe types... artists, dropouts.
这些都不是合法居民 但他们也有自己的想法
These aren't legal dwellings, but they got a hell of a view.
嗯
Hmm.
从你发来的照片来看
In the photos you sent,
卧室里有打斗过的痕迹 对吧?
there were signs of a struggle in the bedroom?
就在这边 我带你们看
That's this way. I'll show you.
嗨
Hi.
Schneiderman女士?
Mrs. Schneiderman?
我叫Defiance
Defiance.
Defiance啊
你是吉普赛人吗?
You are Romani Gypsy?
你怎么知道的?
What do you know about it?
巡回马戏团 我父亲曾参加表演
Carny circuit. My dad was a showman.
- Defiance啊  - 嗯
- So, Defiance.  - Yeah.
画工不错
Quite the painter.
你是谁?
And who are you?
我叫Patrick Jane
Patrick Jane.
联邦调查局请来的 他们说你需要帮助
I was invited by the FBI. They said you need help.
哦...
Oh...
你是个灵媒
you're a psychic.
大家都这么说
So I'm told.
好吧
All right.
看我的手相
Read my palm.
男左女右才行
It only works with a dominant hand.
不行 做不来
No. Can't do it.
我就知道你是骗子
I knew you were a fake.
不是 你不接纳我
No, you're not letting me in.
你很着急找到丈夫
You're anxious about finding your husband,
但你不想某个政府的闲杂人解读你
and you don't want to be read by a gorger from the government.
你感到害怕和孤独...
You're feeling scared and alone...
而且你不相信陌生人
and you don't trust strangers.
- 这不怪你 你不能相信这些人  - Jane
- And I don't blame you. You can't trust these guys.  - Jane.
我是说 他们是好意
I mean, they mean well,
只要你配合他们 就会找到你丈夫的
and they'll find your husband if you let them do their thing.
- 空口白话  - 信不信随你
- Says you.  - Yes, says me.
你为什么让联邦调查局找灵媒呢?
Why are you asking the FBI to meet your spiritual needs?
你没有自己信任的灵媒吗?
Don't you have a trusted psychic of your own?
有 他叫Cleo
I do. Cleo.
但他不接我的电话
But he's not answering my phone calls.
这很奇怪
Hmm. That is odd.
你能找到他吗? 你能找到Abel吗?
Can you find him? Can you find Abel?
你最后一次见他是在哪?
Where was the last place you saw him?
是前天晚上在屋顶上
On the roof, night before last.
你们在屋顶干什么?
What were you doing up there?
和女友们喝杯酒
Sharing a bottle of wine with my girlfriends.
Abel带着笔记本电脑上来了
Abel came up there with his laptop.
他喜欢在屋顶上放松 那里非常祥和
He likes to unwind on the roof. It's peaceful.
我想去看看屋顶
I'd like to take a look at this roof.
门廊尽头的台阶就是
It's the stairs at the end of the hallway.
嗨
Hi.
你干嘛?
What are you doing?
猫眼后面有人
Spyhole went dark.
什么?
What?
我们是联邦调查局的
We're with the FBI.
先生 在过去几周内
Sir, did you see or hear anything unusual
你有没有看到或听到不寻常的动静?
in the last couple weeks?
我早就告诉过你们了 没有
I already told you people, no.
我们是另一个部门的
We're with a different office.
多得像蟑螂一样
So many, like roaches.
人很随和
Nice guy.
他叫Nguyen Hai 是越南难民
His name is Nguyen Hai. He's a Vietnamese refugee.
过去经营一家面馆 现在这房子是他的
He used to run a noodle shop. Now he owns the building.
失踪那晚他在家
He was home the evening of the disappearance,
但他什么都没听到或看到
but he didn't hear or see anything.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know that?
我读过卷宗了
I read the case files.
我以为你对这案子不感兴趣
I thought you weren't interested in the case.
飞机上很无聊
It was a long plane ride.
如果Abel消失那晚是在楼顶
So if Abel came up here the night he disappeared,
为什么卧室是乱的?
why was the bedroom trashed?
我不知道 我从酒吧回来很晚
I don't know. I got home late from the bar.
进来的时候 Abel不见了 房间里一团糟
When I got in, Abel was gone, and our room was wrecked.
他在等人吗?
Was he expecting any visitors?
应该没有
I don't think so.
否则我走之前他会告诉我的
He would have told me before I left.
这是你丈夫的花园
This is your husband's garden.
没错 你怎么知道?
Yeah. How'd you know?
他的能量在这
His energy's here.
他把自己的能量倾注在这座花园里
He pours his energy into this garden
因为他不喜欢做电脑程序员
because he doesn't like being a computer programmer.
没错
That's right.
他在那个世界里感觉被束缚了
He feels trapped in that world.
是的
Yes.
那是个秩序井然的世界
It's an orderly world,
充满规则和数字
full of rules and numbers.
但那不是Abel的世界
But it's not Abel's world.
他将自己视作叛逆者
He sees himself more as a rebel soul.
他真的很喜欢切·格瓦拉
He really loves that Che Guevara guy.
所以他才骑摩托车
Yeah, that's why he rides a motorcycle.
自己种蔬菜
Grows his own vegetables.
所以他才和你结婚
That's why he married you.
就因为我是吉普赛人?
Oh, because I'm a Gypsy?
是啊
Yeah.
因为你有勇气为爱
Because you had the courage to walk away from
离开几个世纪以来的传统
centuries of tradition for love.
你或许不知道 但你给了你丈夫
You may not know it, but you give your husband
做自己的内在勇气
the courage to be who he is on the inside.
Abel还活着吗?
Is Abel alive?
你何不帮我找到他呢?
Why don't you help me find him?
我能感觉到他
I can feel him.
他在哪?
Where is he?
只是形象不清楚
Just not getting a clear read.
我应该怎么做?
What should I do?
这个...
Well...
别告诉他们是我说的
don't tell them I said this,
你应该偷偷溜走立刻通知媒体
but you should sneak off and notify the media right away.
- 懂吗?  - 好的
- Hmm?  - Okay.
然后这个城市能齐心协力帮忙找到他
So that this city can pull together and help find him.
这是你救丈夫性命
That is your only hope
唯一的希望了
at saving your husband's life.
好的
Okay.
去吧
Go.
她去哪?
Where's she going?
她... 想给媒体打电话
She, uh... wants to call the press.
我试图阻止她了
I... I... I tried to stop her.
下楼去
Downstairs.
你真是很想被关回牢里啊
You must really miss that prison cell.
我会试着跟她谈谈
I'll try and talk to her.
你已经说得够多了
You have done enough talking.
嗨
Hi.
Jane回到屋顶后
After Jane returned to the roof,
沿着逃生梯到了南巷
he went down a fire escape to the south alley.
在那里摄像头拍不到他了
And that's where the cameras lose sight of him.
谁负责南边出口?
Who was covering the south exit?
是我 但我看不到小巷的情况
I was. But I didn't have a line of sight to the alley.
那里没有出口 所以我以为...
There are no exits there, so I didn't think...
你以为错了 这会写在你档案里的
You misread the situation. There'll be a note in your file.
是 长官
Yes, ma'am.
Collins不是惟一一个犯错的
Collins wasn't the only one to misread the situation.
你说还有我?
You mean me?
对
Yeah.
你说得没错 我也搞砸了
You're correct. I screwed up, too.
Abbott监督探员会在我的档案里写明的
And Supervising Agent Abbott will note that in my file.
很公平
Fair enough.
那你就和Collins探员负责找Jane吧?
Why don't you and Agent Collins focus on looking for Jane?
你们有内应
You have an insight there.
和纽约分部的Davis配合
Coordinate with Davis in the New York office.
是 长官
Yes, ma'am.
劳驾
Thank you.
这才是真的你吧?
This is the real you, huh?
还是专心找被绑架的人 行吗?
Let's keep our eyes on the prize, shall we?
失踪者Abel Schneiderman
Abel Schneiderman.
我们把他的绑架嫌疑人缩小到了...
We have narrowed his kidnapping suspects...
- 打断一下?  - 三个极端主义组织...
- Excuse me?  - To three extremist groups...
我在这干嘛?
Why am I here?
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
没我的事了 Jane逃走了
I have no business. Jane's gone.
我们会找到他的
We'll find him.
你们大多数都能认出这些人
Uh, most of you will recognize these faces.
他想被找到的时候 你们才能找到他
You're only gonna find him if he wants to be found,
而他显然不想被找到 否则一开始也不会走了
which he doesn't, or he wouldn't have left in the first place.
休息一下
Take five.
告诉我 呃...
Tell me something. Uh...
你帮助Jane逃走了吗?
did you help Jane escape?
我为什么要那么做?
Why would I do that?
你是他的朋友
You're h-his friend.
没错 但我也是一个警察
Yes, I am, but I'm also an officer of the law.
我不是想给你惹麻烦 我只是...
I'm not trying to get you in trouble. I just...
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
我...
I...
我当初很确定已经让他想明白了
I was so certain I had him figured out.
欢迎来到我的世界
Welcome to my life.
你是怎么坚持了这么长时间的?
How did you make it work for so long?
我自己也想过
I've thought about that myself.
我是说 在他消失后
I mean, after he disappeared.
我是怎么坚持这么久的
How I made it work for so long.
答案是什么?
And what's the answer?
我不知道
I have no idea.
你们俩谈过恋爱吗?
Were you two ever involved?
这个问题很奇怪
That's a strange question.
你为什么问我这个?
Why would you ask me that?
呃...
Uh...
没什么 我只是... 我...
no reason. I just... I...
呃... 算了吧
Uh, nev... Never mind.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
等你
Waiting for you.
做什么?
To do what?
注意到我
Notice me.
你是谁?
Who are you?
Jason Wylie 初级信息分析师
Jason Wylie. Uh, Junior I.T. Analyst.
我在信息部门工作
I work in I.T.
分析东西
Analyzing stuff.
好吧
Okay.
你想干嘛 Jason?
What do you want, Jason?
上级要求我们专心为Schneiderman失踪案
Uh, we were told to focus I.T. support
提供信息支持
on the Schneiderman case,
但午餐时间是我自己的 对吧?
But I'm my own man at lunch, right?
所以我偷偷花时间找了下Patrick Jane
So I stole some satellite time to hunt for Patrick Jane.
看我找到了什么
Look what I found.
这是22分钟前
This was taken 22 minutes ago
在布鲁克林上空的卫星采集到的
from a satellite over Brooklyn.
你真认为是Jane吗? 不是什么玩笑?
You think it's really Jane? It's not a trick?
绝对是Jane
That's Jane.
立刻通知纽约分部
Notify New York right away.
谁找到的?
Who found this?
Wylie分析师 在他休息时间
Analyst Wylie. On his own time.
谁是Wylie分析师?
Who is Analyst Wylie?
就在那儿
Right there.
过来吧
Feel free to join us.
你是自发搜索的?
You took this initiative on your own?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
那就看看你在主队上能做些什么吧
Well, let's see what you can do on the primary team.
Stanley 给Wylie在大房间里安排一张桌子
Stanley, find Wylie a desk in the bullpen.
趴下!
Down!
Get down!
脸朝地面!
Face down on the street!
谢谢
Thank you.
嗯
Mnh.
恭喜啊
Congratulations.
你骗到我了 把戏不错
You got one over on me. It's a nice stunt.
这下子你高兴了?
You feel better now?
嗯... 不 你吵醒我了
Mm... no. You woke me up.
我就不明白了
I don't get you.
你已经追查到 并且杀了宿敌
You hunted down and killed your enemy.
你干嘛非要找新的敌人?
Why are you making new ones?
呃 你说得对
Eh, you're right.
我不应该逃避
Running away was a mistake.
现在我准备好接受新工作了
I'm ready to discuss the job offer now.
没有新工作了
There is no offer, not anymore.
不可能 我们说好的
Nonsense. Let's talk.
我要把你送回德州
I am taking you back to Texas.
接下来的一周 你会面临着
And next week you'll be indicted for the murder
谋杀Thomas Mcallister的指控
of Thomas Mcallister,
以及其它指控
among other charges.
守卫
Guard.
你们找到尸体了吗?
You cats find the body yet?
什么尸体?
What body?
藏在Abel Schneiderman大厦房顶上的尸体
The body hidden on the roof of Abel Schneiderman's building.
你看到了?
You saw it?
没有 但花园旁边
No, but there's a large pile of soil
有一堆土
just by the garden.
冬天快到了
Winter is almost upon us,
要那么多土干什么?
so what is that soil doing there?
答案是显而易见的
That's a rhetorical question.
因为Schneiderman女士的灵媒Cleo...
The soil is there to make room for Cleo...
占据了泥土的地方
Mrs. Schneiderman's psychic.
他和她丈夫都不见了
He went missing the same time as her husband.
你在说什么呢?
What are you talking about?
Abel发现妻子和灵媒有染
Abel found out his wife was sleeping with her psychic,
所以在卧室了杀了他
so he killed him in the bedroom.
但Abel没有车 所以他只能分尸
But Abel doesn't own a car, so he cut up the body
然后埋在了花园里
into pieces and buried them in the garden.
他根本没有被绑架
Your kidnap victim isn't kidnapped.
他是凶手 已经逃跑了
He's a killer. And he's on the run.
你很厉害
You're good.
谢谢
Thank you.
你编故事很厉害
A good liar.
哦...
Eh...
希望他不是在耍我们玩
I really hope this isn't his idea of a joke.
有这个可能
There is that chance.
但也有可能他说得对
There's also the chance that he's right.
如果说这份工作让我失去了什么
If there's one thing that this job kills inside,
那就是信任感
it's a sense of trust.
我都忘了信任是什么感觉的
I almost forgot what it feels like.
嘿 照着点这里
Hey, let me get some light over here.
找到了
Well, there we go.
嘿
Hey.
他们竟然给我分了一张桌子
I can't believe they gave me a desk.
你可以叫我"小狼"
You can call me "the coyote."
我不想叫
I don't think so.
在楼下他们都是这么叫我的
That's just what they call me downstairs.
我也不知道为什么 他们从没说过
Don't ask me why, though. They never told me.
你叫Wylie
Your name's Wylie.
嗯
Yeah.
就是那个Wiley Coyote
Wiley Coyote.
是"宾尼兔"动画片里的?
"Road runner," the cartoon?
不 来自爱尔兰语
No, it's Irish, I think.
早上好 Stanley探员
Uh, good morning, Agent Stanley.
嘿...
Hey...
你知道宾尼兔和小狼的故事吗?
Do you know the road runner and the coyote?
知道 达拉斯市的皮条客
Yeah. Sex traffickers in Dallas.
还有皮条客的动画片?
There's a cartoon about sex trafficking?
嘿 Cho 有空吗?
Hey, Cho, you got a minute?
嗯
Yeah.
昨晚Abbott和我去了趟布鲁克林
Abbott and I went to Brooklyn last night.
房顶上藏了具尸体
There was a body hidden on the roof.
Jane说得对
Jane was right.
他一般都没错 查到死者身份了吗?
He usually is. You get an I.D.?
还在调查 不过应该像Jane说的
We're waiting on forensics, but it appears to be
是Schneiderman女士的灵媒
Mrs. Schneiderman's psychic, just like Jane said.
局长希望能把他调回来查案
The director wants me to bring him back on the case.
挺好的啊
That's a good call.
他让我们出丑
He made fools of us.
这是他的惯用伎俩
It won't be the last time.
我怎么才能控制得了他?
How do I get him under control?
你控制不了他的 Jane就是这样
You don't. Jane is what he is.
他会将所有人为他所用
He'll use you to turn every situation to his advantage.
那你说我该怎么做?
So what would you suggest I do?
你也利用他
Use him to your advantage.
- 找到尸体了?  - 是的
- Found the body?  - Yes.
Cleo Ascencio 纽约市灵媒
Cleo Ascencio, New York psychic,
占星术士 也是医师
astrologer, healer.
还在花盆里发现了钢锯
Also found a hacksaw hidden in the planters,
与Abel工具箱里的工具品牌一样
Same brand as the other tools in Abel's kit,
上面发现了受害者的血迹
with traces of the victim's blood.
Abel杀了妻子的情人然后逃跑
So Abel killed his wife's lover and ran away,
和... 我说的一样
just... like I said.
看起来是的
Well, it appears so.
别太自责
Oh. Don't beat yourselves up.
你们自己也能想明白的
You would have figured it out eventually.
我说的是"看起来是的"
I said, "appears so."
他刚刚收到了一封勒索信
He just received a ransom note.
是一封直接送到
A third-class letter sent directly
Abel Schneiderman办公室的平信
to Abel Schneiderman's office.
都什么年头了 绑架犯怎么会寄信?
What kind of kidnapper uses snail mail?
这招很不错
It's smart, really.
老式手法 难以追踪
Low-tech, old school, no electronic footprint.
身份不明的绑架犯想要一千万美元
Unidentified kidnappers want $10 million
在午夜前汇入一个海外账户
deposited into an overseas account by midnight,
否则他会把Schneiderman交个出价最高者
or they will sell Schneiderman to the highest bidder.
接下来他们会
Next step would be a cyber-attack
攻击美联储
on the Federal Reserve.
- 需要我通知情报局吗?  - 好的
- You want me to notify Secret Service?  - Please do.
不对
This isn't right.
根本没有绑架犯
There are no kidnappers.
我漏掉了什么?
What am I missing?
也许Abel伪造了自己被绑架
Maybe Abel faked his own kidnapping
想要拿到钱逃往国外
to get money to escape the country.
推理得很好 Lisbon 这是现在最可能的情况
That's very good, Lisbon. That is the best theory yet,
但仍然有错误
but it's wrong, too.
我要到阁楼看看
I need another look at that loft.
你当真? 再去布鲁克林一次?
Really? Back to Brooklyn again?
是的
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
别担心 我不会逃跑的
Don't worry. I won't escape.
我不担心 如果你再逃跑...
Oh, I'm not worried. If you walk away this time...
我知道 我后半生就得在监狱里度过了
I know. I'll end up spending the rest of my life in prison.
不
No.
我会毙了你的
I'll shoot you.
嗯
Mm.
看 这里有"机场购物广场"
Oh, look, they have "skymall."
"机场购物广场"啊
"Skymall."
好了 Lisbon 有什么事吗?
Okay, Lisbon, what's the matter?
是你有问题
You.
是因为我在办公室里说的那些吗?
Was it that comment I made in the bullpen?
我真的觉得你推理得很对
Because I think it's a really good theory.
我才不在乎那些
I don't care about that.
你又一次逃跑了 Jane
You ran away again, Jane.
不只是从联邦调查局逃跑 更是从我身边逃跑
Not from the FBI. You ran away from me.
嗯 但我又回来了
Yeah, but I ran back.
我怎么会知道你会回来?
How was I supposed to know?
我以为你又永远消失了
I thought you were gone again forever.
好吧 你说得对 我... 我错了 Lisbon
Okay, you're right. I... I'm sorry, Lisbon.
我... 我太不顾你的感受了
I... I didn't think about you.
嗯 你一向如此
Well, you rarely do.
哦 不是的
Well, that's not true.
我也为你做了点事 我... 我拒绝了联邦调查局的邀请
I made you one of my demands. I'm... I'm not joining the FBI.
除非他们给你份工作
Unless they make you a job offer.
又来了
That's my point.
你凭什么认为我想和你公事?
What makes you think I want to work with you again?
你咄咄逼人 不好相处
You are difficult and exhausting,
我可不想自己后半辈子
and maybe I don't want to put the rest of my life
都为你收拾烂摊子
on hold to be your sidekick.
你想过这些吗?
Have you ever even thought about that?
没... 没
No... no.
我没想过这些
I hadn't considered it.
你以为你是为我好
You think you know what's good for my life,
但两年来 你踪迹全无
but you haven't been a part of my life for two years.
所以赶紧把这个案子结了 我要回家
So let's get this case wrapped up so I can go home.
你竟敢说我背叛了Abel!
How dare you think that I would cheat on Abel!
还是和Cleo?!
And with Cleo?!
不 我... 我读的不是你的思想 是你丈夫的
No, I... I wasn't reading you. I was reading your husband.
你这么迷人 而你丈夫是个程序猿
You're a catch. Your husband's a computer nerd
假装自己是高富帅 想要和你在一起
pretending to be a rebel to try and hang on to you.
那样的人如果觉得自己被骗了 很容易走极端的
Men like that snap when they feel betrayed.
是的 Abel很爱吃醋
It's true. Abel is very jealous
没有安全感 很懦弱
and insecure and he overcompensates,
但你忘了一点
but you missed one detail.
你们很相爱
You're in love.
他是我的英雄
He's my little lion,
我绝不会和其他男人上床的
and I would never sleep with another man.
我知道了
I see that now.
- 我想一个人静一静  - 好吧
- I would like to be alone.  - All right.
请走吧
Please leave.
好的
Okay.
你还认为是Abel杀死Cleo的吗?
Do you still think Abel killed Cleo?
是他杀的 一时冲动
Oh, I know he did. Guy's a hothead.
强壮的肌肉 脖子上的纹身
Those swollen biceps and neck tattoos.
这些根据都表明他脱不了干系
The mere hint of an affair would set that guy off.
Abel失踪那晚 她的灵媒为什么会来这里?
Why was her psychic here the night Abel disappeared?
那晚Defiance一直和朋友们在外面
Defiance was out with her friends all night.
他去顶楼干嘛呢
There was no reason for him to be at the loft.
Cleo Ascencio是一个很夸张的名字
Cleo Ascencio. It's such a theatrical name.
你觉得是真名吗?
You think it's real?
是真名 我们验了指纹
It is. We ran his fingerprints.
- 我猜没有犯罪记录?  - 什么都没有
- Let me guess. Clean record?  - Spotless.
你想说什么 Lisbon?
What are you suggesting, Lisbon?
Ascencio这个名字... 听起来像古巴人
Ascencio... it sounds Cuban.
在古巴有个违法活动
There's a scam that they do in Cuba.
只要给中介一大笔钱
Brokers charge large sums of money
他们可以通过手术修改你的指纹
to surgically modify fingerprints.
把你的左右手指纹互换
They swap the right fingertips and the left.
每次都能骗过移民局
It fools immigration every time.
你怎么知道的?
How do you know that?
我可是警长
I'm a police chief.
一直闲着 只能读卷宗
With a lot of reading time on my hands.
我按照Lisbon警长说的
I did what Chief Lisbon suggested
把左右手的指纹互换搜查
and ran the left-hand fingerprints for the right,
然后找到了
And it worked.
Cleo Ascencio摇身一变...
Cleo Ascencio transforms into...
成为Jose Martinez
Jose Martinez.
他是谁?
And who is he?
一个骗子 哈瓦那街头的小混混
A fraud. A street hustler from havana.
他以扒窃为生 直到他偷到一个
Made a living picking pockets until he stole a wallet
卡斯特罗的部长的钱包
from one of Castro's ministers.
现在他被国际刑警通缉
Now he's wanted by the P.N.R.
是Jose Martinez?
Jose Martinez?
他从古巴偷渡出来 然后在这里开店
He fled Cuba and set up shop here.
好吧 他改过名字
Okay, so he changed his name.
但这不能说明他是个骗子
That doesn't mean he's a fraud.
你觉得你丈夫失踪那晚
You have any idea why he was in your loft
他为什么会到阁楼上?
the night your husband went missing?
有时候Cleo觉得有所发现
Sure. Uh, Cleo would drop by sometimes
他就会过来告诉我
when he thought he had an insight I should here.
如果你不在家的话
Now, if you weren't here,
Abel会让他进来吗?
would Abel let him into the building?
不一定非要Abel给开门 Cleo自己有密码的
He wouldn't have to. Cleo had the security code.
他自己就可以进来
He would just buzz himself in.
这就可以解释了
Well, that explains what he was doing
- 他两夜前在你的卧室里干什么  - 解释了吗?
- in your bedroom two nights ago.  - It does?
热读术
Hot reading.
这是灵媒江湖骗子的基本功
It's the bread and butter of the spiritual flimflam man.
事先通过私人物品进行了解
You gather personal effects on your subject in advance,
再以通灵术的形式向客户展示
and then you present them as psychic revelations.
Martinez上来看看Defiance是否需要读心
Martinez came up to see if Defiance wanted a reading.
但她出去喝酒了 Abel又在屋顶上
But she was out drinking, and Abel was on the roof.
于是他便上屋里来偷窥一番
So he came up into the house and he took a little snoop.
Abel下来时
When Abel came downstairs,
正好撞见你的灵媒在你卧室里
he caught your psychic in the bedroom
便认定你和他有外遇
and assumed you were sleeping with him.
好吧 就算这样
Okay. Fine.
但这根本没解释
But none of that explains
谁把Abel从大楼掳走的
who took Abel from the building.
的确没有 因为我根本不认为
No, it doesn't, because I don't think
Abel的双脚曾离开过这栋楼
Abel ever left the building.
如果我没猜错的话
If my suspicion is correct,
他还在这楼里 而且胳膊腿还全乎着呢
he is still here, and he is still very much alive.
咱们得留个人在这陪Defiance
One of us needs to stay here with Defiance.
- 我留下来  - 你不想参与逮捕?
- I'll stay.  - You don't want in on the bust?
不了 我们仨已经合力见证过够多的了 你去吧
Nah, the three of us have done a lot of busts together. You go.
没有什么比跟Jane一起实施抓捕更带劲的了
There's nothing like a takedown with Jane.
小菜
Shucks.
请吧?
Shall we?
一...
One...
二...
Two...
三
Three.
你们知道现在几点了吗?
Do you know what time it is?
瞧? 生来紧张多疑
See? Distractible and paranoid by nature.
若不知来者是谁 便谁也不许进门
Can't let anyone pass this door without knowing who it is.
到底算什么意思啊?
What the hell is going on out here?
- 问得好  - 发生了一起谋杀
- Glad you asked.  - There's been a murder.
你们已经说过了 Schneiderman死了
And you said already. Schneiderman.
不 他只是被绑架了 被杀的是另一个人
No, he was kidnapped. Another man's been murdered,
但你早就知道了 对吧?
But you know that, right?
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你当然知道 你什么都知道
Sure, you do. You know everything,
你甚至知道Schneiderman现在在哪
including where Schneiderman is right now.
我什么都不知道
I don't know anything.
他就在你屋里 对吧?
He's in your apartment, isn't he?
可能在浴室 不 你很看重自己的隐私
Probably in the bathroom. No. You value your privacy.
要我说... 是塞进壁橱里了
I'm gonna say... stashed in a closet.
小心点 Jane
Watch out, Jane.
Nguyen 开门!
Open the door, Nguyen!
呃 来个人把门撞开吧?
Uh, somebody gonna break the door?
去吧
Go ahead.
好 我准备好了
All right, I'm ready.
你走右边路
Break right.
我来对付他 你去找Schneiderman
I got him. Go find Schneiderman.
跟我说说 Abel
So, tell me, Abel.
Jose Martinez死亡的那晚
Did you invite Jose Martinez
你有邀请他来你的公寓吗?
into your loft the night of his death?
没有 我从屋顶下来
No. I came down from the roof,
看到他在我们的卧室里
and he was there in our bedroom.
他之前在干什么?
And what was he doing?
我也在纳闷
That's what I wanted to know.
嘿!
Hey!
嘿! Abel!
Hey! Abel!
呃 不是你想的那样
Uh, this isn't what it looks like.
- 你在干什么?  - 呃... 没什么 瞧?
- What are you doing?  - Uh... nothing. See?
Defiance呢? Defiance?!
Where's Defiance? Defiance?!
她不在 是我自己进来的! 我该走了
She's not here. I let myself in! I should go.
你哪儿也别想去!
You're not going anywhere!
我错了 好吗? 我真的该走了
I'm sorry, okay? I should go.
我当时有些失控
I kind of lost it.
好了! 好了!
All right! All right!
我走!
I'll go!
他被毛毯套绊倒
His foot got caught in the shag throw.
他... 他的头撞到了咖啡桌
His... his head hit the coffee table.
太可怕了
It was horrible.
那你为什么不报警?
And why didn't you call the police?
在家里横躺着个死人的时候?
With a dead man on the floor?
你刚才描述的叫做过失杀人
What you described is involuntary manslaughter.
你原本关六个月就可以出来的
You would have been out in six months.
然后呢?
Then what?
我是为联邦政府工作的 这样我的职业生涯就完了
I work for the Feds. My career would have been over.
Defiance也会离我而去
I would have lost Defiance.
于是我决定毁尸灭迹
That's when I decided to hide the body.
而因为那扇吱呀作响的过道门
And the squeaky hallway door made sure
你一直听得到Schneiderman家的动静
you always heard the Schneidermans.
于是你便看到了
That is how you came to see
Abel拖着一具尸体上了屋顶
Abel hauling a body to the roof.
他是谁?
Who is he?
不过是个罪有应得的人罢了
Just somebody who deserved what he got.
这... 只是场噩梦
This... this is a bad dream.
Nguyen先生 回去睡觉就好
Just go back to bed, Mr. Nguyen.
我不想睡
I'm not sleepy.
你想怎样?
What do you want?
你想要钱? 好吧
You want money? Fine.
我会给你5000美元
I'll give you $5,000
让你忘记今晚发生的事
to forget everything you saw here tonight.
你是那个为联邦政府工作的
You're that security contractor
安保承包商
for the federal government.
没错
Yeah.
对政府而言 你到底值多少钱呢?
Exactly how much are you worth to the government?
我们的同事Jane先生怀疑
Our colleague Mr. Jane suspected
你可是大有来头
there was more to you than meets the eye.
你脸上的伤疤根本不是
You didn't get those scars on your face
开面条店弄的
from running a noodle shop.
你很早就是黑帮的人了 是青龙帮吗?
You're a gangster from way back. Green dragons?
"生来嗜血"
"Born to kill."
是纽约史上最血腥的街头帮派
It was the bloodiest street gang in New York history.
成员都是越南的难民
All Vietnamese refugees.
我听说你们在上世纪80年代控制了整个唐人街
I hear you guys owned Chinatown in the '80s.
是整个纽约
We owned New York.
为了记录在案 最后一件事
One last story for the record books.
一名"生来嗜血"的原成员
How an original member of B.T.K.
是如何差点要了联邦政府一千万的
almost took the Feds for $10 million.
你最好老实交代
Give me that confession.
把笔给我
Give me the pen.
你想和我谈谈?
You wanted to talk to me?
你脑子很灵
You have a sharp mind.
人们也喜欢你
And people like you.
当然了 是部分人
Some people.
嗯...
Well...
我之前还不觉得
I didn't think so before,
但现在我发觉这种关系可以长期维持下去
but I can see this arrangement working on a permanent basis.
我也挺喜欢你的 Dennis
I like you, too, Dennis.
我也能想象以后和你合作的样子
And I can see working with you in the future,
但必须按照我的条款 你也知道的
but only on my terms, and you know that.
是啊 我们已经谈过了 不存在什么协议
Yeah, we've been through this. There's no deals.
没有要求 没有谈判
No demands, no negotiations.
我们会为你提供一份职业 洗清历史
We are offering you a career, a clean slate,
为你的生活制造一个转机
a chance to make a difference.
你很会讨价还价 Dennis
You drive a hard bargain, Dennis.
好吧 不说之前的条款了
Okay, pet leopard's off the table.
不管它了
Forget about that.
但我要完全赦免 还有通风扇
But I need the full pardon. And the airstream.
对了 我还要一个沙发
And I need a couch, man,
因为这边什么东西都冷冰冰硬邦邦的
'cause everything is cold and hard around here.
还有...
And...
我要你为Lisbon提供一份工作
I need a job offer for Lisbon.
我相信有些人
I am sure that some people
会觉得你的这一面很讨人喜欢...
find this side of you endearing...
但我可不是其中之一
but I'm not one of them.
我会在电视上关注你的谋杀案审判的
I'll be following your murder trial on the TV.
祝你好运
Good luck.
好吧
Okay.
多谢
Thank you.
对了 好好看看邮件
Oh, enjoy your mail.
先生们 停一下
Fellas. Stop right there.
Jane啊...
Jane...
你这是从哪弄来的?
Where did you get this from?
是Gail Bertram藏着的一枚微存储器
Oh, a thumb drive Gail Bertram was hiding.
这事我还是头一次听说
This is the first I'm hearing about it.
那是因为这是我第一次开口
It's the first I've talked of it.
这些都是布雷克组织的成员
These are all the members of the Blake Association.
没错
Correct.
我猜Bertram留着是为了保险起见
I figured Bertram was keeping it as insurance.
可是这些人我们要么逮捕了 要么辞退了啊
Well, we've arrested or retired all of these people.
的确...
Yes, you have...
除了我涂掉的那些
except the ones that I've blacked out.
那些人你还没有抓到
Those ones you haven't caught.
我们把他们一网打尽了
We caught them all.
这么有自信? 那看来是Bertram自己搞错了吧
Did you? Well, I guess Bertram was wrong then.
把名单给我
Give me the names.
不过是几个法官 一个国会议员
A couple of judges, a congressman,
- 几个联邦调查局探员  - 我要名单
- several FBI agents.  - Names.
有几个来头可不小
Big names, some of them.
万一那份名单泄露给媒体
If that list ever got out to the press,
那可是把你们推向风口浪尖了 对吧?
it'd cause all kinds of turmoil, wouldn't it?
- 你在威胁我?  - 才没有
- Are you threatening me?  - Oh, no.
只不过是指出我们都具备带给对方
Just pointing out that we both have the power
不幸的能力罢了
to create misery.
好吧
Okay.
你把名单交出来 我们就同意
You give me the names, and we'll agree
你条款的所有内容
to all of your terms on the contract.
我一旦交出名单 你就会出尔反尔
If I give you the names, you'll break the contract.
你已经这么做过一次了
You've already done it once.
那你怎么提议?
What do you propose?
我提议你向我的条款屈服
I propose that you surrender to my terms,
也只有等我与你的合同
and when I'm finished with your contract,
签完之后
and only then,
我才会交出名单
I will give you the names.
把他带走
Get him out of here.
嗯...
Mm...
- 那个...  - 嗯?
- Well...  - Hmm?
你这次做到了
You did it this time.
你反将了联邦调查局一军
You brought the FBI to its knees.
是吗?
Did I?
他们同意了你的所有要求
They conceded to all your demands.
每条都是 你怎么做到的?
Every single one. How did you do it?
还记得我们在Bertram的酒窖里
Well, remember that thumb drive
发现的微存储器吗?
we found in Bertram's wine cellar?
那个加密数据库?
The encrypted database?
是布雷克组织的成员名单
It's a list of Blake Association members.
我利用它作为我的筹码
I used it as leverage.
但我们一直没能破解
But we never broke the encryption.
是啊 可联邦调查局又不知道
Yeah, the FBI doesn't know that.
所以你逃跑了
That's why you escaped.
制造了一份假名单
To create a bogus list of names.
还吃了个培根热狗
And to enjoy a bacon-wrapped hot dog.
我得说 非常了不起
I have to say, I am impressed.
- 你将了联邦调查局一军  - 小菜
- You outplayed the FBI.  - No contest.
他们有没有跟你说我什么时候开始工作?
Did they tell you when I start work?
是"我们"
When we start.
我们?
We?
那你的工作怎么办?
What about your job?
- 算了吧 太无聊了  - 是啊 我就说的嘛
- Nah. It was boring.  - Yeah, I told you.
没错 但你无权这么说
Yeah. But you had no right to.
那是我的生活 我才有发言权
It's my life, and I'll decide what to do with it.
- 那你真是相当明智  - 根本没有别的选择啊
- And you decided correctly.  - There was never any choice.
别这样 会很有趣的
Oh, come on. It'll be fun.
看看咱们能捅出多大的篓子
Let's see what kind of trouble we can make.
我要送你一样东西
I got you something.
给我的?
For me?
嗯
Mm-hmm.
你给我买了袜子
You got me socks.
华盛顿手工缝制
Handmade in Washington.
太贴心了...
Oh...
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调：有个饭团
时间轴：pisces夜
翻译：笑点滴 波特妹子 初见 捞小盐
校对：爱犀利馒头叔的影子